Guide to the Metropolitan Council on Housing Records TAM.173
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III. 2002 through 2007 Accretions, 1939-1999; 84792; 22 Linear Feet
  - Housing Crimes Trial Reel #8, Dec 6, 1970 and Oct 13, 1971; 582977 (Box 27, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Housing Crimes Trial Reel #9, Dec 6, 1970 and Oct 13, 1971; 582978 (Box 27, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Housing Crimes Trial Reel #10, Dec 6, 1970 and Oct 13, 1971; 582979 (Box 27, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Housing Crimes Trial Reel #11, Dec 6, 1970 and Oct 13, 1971; 582980 (Box 27, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Housing Crimes Trial Reel #12, Dec 6, 1970 and Oct 13, 1971; 582981 (Box 27, Box TAM Shared Access Box 1)
  - Air-check of Housing Notebook for Esther, Jul 4, 1981; 582375; 1 Two-track stero traditional MOR (Box 27)
  - Esther Rand Slide Show, undated; 582376; contains 1 slide show tray with slides (Box 27)
  - Articles and letters-to-the-editor, pro and con, on Jane Benedict, mostly re: profile in "Our Town", undated; 85199 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Esther Rand: Naturalization papers, marriage artifacts, misc. letters, undated; 85198 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Position papers: MCH, 1963; 85197 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Build Public Housing Committee: MCH, undated; 85196 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Annual Assembly, 1962; 85195 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Conference, 1960-1961; 85194 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Press, policy statements, 1960-1962; 85193 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - WBAI announcement, undated; 85192 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Policy statement: Cadman Plaza, undated; 85191 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Public Housing Committee, 1965; 85190 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Press releases, undated; 85189 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - NAACP, undated; 85188 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous non-MCH, undated; 85187 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Washington Square Neighbors, 1950s; 85186 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Legislative bulletins, 1966; 85185 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Legislative Committee, 1965; 85184 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Squatters: Correspondence, leaflets and articles, undated; 85183 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Squatters: Correspondence, leaflets and articles, undated; 85182 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Squatters: Correspondence, leaflets and articles, undated; 85181 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Washington Square Tenants Association, undated; 85180 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Washington Square Tenants Council: Correspondence, legal papers, reports of meetings, 1960s; 85179 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Yorkville, East Harlem: leaflet masters, undated; 85178 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Central Brooklyn: leaflet masters, undated; 85177 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Washington Heights: leaflet masters, undated; 85176 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - West Harlem: leaflet, undated; 85175 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - West Queens Branch: Correspondence, articles, undated; 85174 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - MCH documents, including:Flyer for state hearing (1986), MCH constitution, Brooklyn branch flyer; Request to speak at budget hearing (1974); Letter to NY Times(1974); Press release (1964); Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR) hearing flyer (1986); Undated press release (1970s: Rockefeller); Tenant News(1969); MCH Maximum Base Rent (MBR) flyer (1995); Anti-Giuliani flyer (1997); "A Program for Housing in the Public Domain" flyer (undated); Picket flyer (undated); testimony on NYC NOW program (1992); Testimony on Senior Citizen Rent Increase Exemption (SCRIE) hearing (1992); Testimony on lead paint abatement (1992); Testimony on city-owned building rules (1992), 1970s-1997; 85173 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - City Council testimony, letters, etc., 1978-1979; 85172 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, including:Meeting minutes (1959); Demo flyer on Masanyk Towers (1968); Letter to editor by Esther Rand re: Senator Robert F. Kennedy's "slum plan", 1959-1968; 85171 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Penn Square South, undated; 85170 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Cooper Square, 1959-1961; 85169 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous, including: Letter to Rockefeller (1961); Statement against demolition (early 1960s); Papers of Organized Tenants, Inc (1960); The New York Tenants Association; Lower East Side flyer against Cleary block on Madison Street; Yorkville SOH (1961); Goldin testimony at hearing (1961); Villager article on Jacobs speaking at MCH conference (1961); Housing Emergency Legislation Program (HELP); Opposition to 15% increase (1961); MCH bylaws and constitution (1962); Housing News(1956); Conference pamphlets (1959-1963); Morningside Citizens Committee (1960), 85168 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - Housing and Development Board: MCH letters and proposals, 1960; 85167 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Mitchell-Lama, 1970s; 85166 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Bellevue South urban renewal fight, 1964; 85165 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Mitchell-Lama Coalition: Barbaro, 1975; 85164 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Franklin Plaza Tenants Association (Mitchell-Lama) (MCH affiliate), 1970s; 85163 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Albany: MCH lobbying trip, 1977; 85162 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Legislative agendas and Resolutions adopted by Freedom Conference (1963), 1960s; 85161 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Urban renewal, rent subsidies, rehabilitation, letters, flyers, etc., undated; 85160 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Ruppert Renewal (Ruppert Brewery Site in Yorkville): MCH organizing and newspaper clippings on renewal site), 1960s-1980s; 85159 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Ruppert Renewal (Ruppert Brewery Site in Yorkville): MCH organizing and newspaper clippings on renewal site), 1960s-1980s; 85158 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Smoke detectors: Law requiring them and the controversy over ionization-type detectors, 1980s; 85157 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Smoke detectors: Law requiring them and the controversy over ionization-type detectors, 1980s; 85156 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Smoke detectors: Law requiring them and the controversy over ionization-type detectors, 1980s; 85155 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Yorkville Save Our Homes and MCH anti-demolition urban renewal fight in Yorkville: YSOH founding organization of MCH, 1955-1961; 85154 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - MCH's first constitution, plus notes from Constitutional Conference (December 5, 1959), 85153 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Gramercy Neighbors, 1959; 85152 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Housing brochures, 1950s; 85151 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Property owners: Anti-Title I and Rent Control, 1957; 85150 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Black Struggle: MCH involvement with Congress on Racial Equality (CORE), Urban League, etc., 1962-1965; 85149 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Housing Crimes Trial, 1970; 85148 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Housing Crimes Trial: Newspaper clippings, 1970; 85147 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Coalition Against Rent Increase Pass-alongs (CARIP), 1984-1985; 85146 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Coalition Against Rent Increase Pass-alongs (CARIP), 1984-1985; 85145 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - MCH Conference, 1981-1982; 85144 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - MCH Convention of members, 1983; 85143 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper clippings and flyers, 1960s; 85142 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Position papers, fact sheets, and flyers, 1970s; 85141 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings on MCH, 1979-1980; 85140 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - National Tenants Union, Jul 1981; 85139 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - No Service, No Love (play produced by MCH at City Hall), 1977; 85138 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - NY State Tenants and Neighbors, 1983; 85137 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Mitchell-Lama Committee, 1970s; 85136 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Fundraising/25th Anniversary, 1983; 85135 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Citywide Rent Strike, 1981; 85134 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Harlem Branch of MCH, 1970s; 85133 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - MCH 6th Annual Conference, 1964; 85132 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - MCH letters on urban renewal sites, Title I, Battery Park, etc., 1961; 85131 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Esther Rand letters to editors, politicians, 1970s; 85130 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Esther Rand Legislature file: bills and position on bills, 1974; 85129 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - City and suburban homes: Flyers, MCH letters, testimony, etc., 1985-1990; 85128 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Coalition to Re-Plan the Westside Urban Renewal Area: MCH part of, 1973-1975; 85127 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Conservation (neighborhood conservation program): includes Chelsea Save our Homes and Business Committee (Jane Wood), 1963-1964; 85126 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Coalition for a Moratorium on Evictions, 1987; 85125 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - City Planning: includes Planners for Equal Opportunity, 1970s; 85124 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Hall Tenants: Fight to preserve live-in studios at Carnegie Hall, 1981-1982; 85123 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Engine Company 17: Lower East Side Firehouse, 1991; 85122 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Committee for Independent Political Action (CIPA), 1966; 85121 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association (MCH affiliate), 1988-1992; 85120 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Morningside Tenants Federation (MCH affiliate), 1971-1985; 85119 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Neighbors in Action/Vecinos en Action (MCH affiliate), undated; 85118 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - MCH publication from Wagner administration, 1960s; 85117 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Yorkville Save Our Homes brochure, 1950s?; 85116 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Rent Strikes, undated; 85115 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Rent Strikes: General material, 1970-1973; 85114 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Rent Strikes: General material, 1970-1973; 85113 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Rent Strikes: Newsletters and leaflets, 1970-1973; 85112 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Rent Strikes: General material, 1973-1975; 85111 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Rent Strikes, 1970s; 85110 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Rent Strikes, 1980s; 85109 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Branch and building files: Bronx, Brooklyn, East Side;Building files: East Side, 1980s-1990s; 85108 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Midtown branch files, undated; 85107 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - East Side building files, undated; 85106 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Lower East Side building files, undated; 85105 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Lower East Side building files, undated; 85104 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - East Side and West Side building files, undated; 85103 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - East Side Tenants Council;Lower East Side branch and building files, undated; 85102 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Bronx and Brooklyn building files, undated; 85101 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Grand Concourse (Bronx), Queens, and Midtown building files, undated; 85100 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Lower East Side building files, undated; 85099 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - East Side branch and building files, undated; 85098 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - RENA, undated; 85097 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and flyers, undated; 85096 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Analysis of Rent Control from the tenant's viewpoint, undated; 85095 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Lenox Terrace clippings file (before buildings were built), undated; 85094 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous MCH, undated; 85093 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Legislation materials (MCH), 1960s; 85092 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - MCH statement before City Planning Commission on Battery Park City, 1961; 85091 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - MCH statement before City Planning Commission on Tompkins Square Area, 1963; 85090 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - MCH Executive Board minutes and notices, 1960-1961; 85089 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - MCH Constitution and Bylaws, 1962; 85088 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Tompkins Square Project: Urban Renewal, 1963; 85087 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - MCH publications, 1960s; 85086 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - MCH statements, undated; 85085 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Statements on relocation: public proposals, undated; 85084 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Vacant land, undated; 85083 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Seward Park extension, undated; 85082 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Renewal Proposals: Articles for Brooklyn, undated; 85081 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Conference literature, undated; 85080 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - MCH Annual conference, 1963; 85079 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Lower East Side Neighborhood Association, undated; 85078 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Cooper Square Committee, 1963; 85077 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Urban Renewal Panel, undated; 85076 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Institute for Policy Studies, undated; 85075 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Participation Loan, undated; 85074 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Park West Village, undated; 85073 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - MCH 25th Anniversary, undated; 85072 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Bay Ridge Branch, undated; 85071 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Homefront: Abandonment report, undated; 85070 (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Bay Ridge Branch, undated; 85069 (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Lower East Side Masters, undated; 85068 (Box 43, Folder 40)
  - June 23, undated; 85067 (Box 43, Folder 41)
  - Rent Guidelines Board flyer, 1989; 85066 (Box 43, Folder 42)
  - Anti-Warehousing Demo, 1989; 85065 (Box 43, Folder 43)
  - Rent Guidelines Board, 1996; 85064 (Box 43, Folder 44)
  - Rent Guidelines Board, 1995; 85063 (Box 43, Folder 45)
  - Rent Law, 1994; 85062 (Box 43, Folder 46)
  - Workshop on "Spiegel Law", undated; 85061 (Box 43, Folder 47)
  - Shelter Force: Tenants' History Project, 1978; 85060 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Small Building Committee, 1980s; 85059 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Spanish Language articles, undated; 85058 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - The Tenant readers' survey, 1993; 85057 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Publicity workshops, 1971-1972; 85056 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Tenant Emancipation Rally, 1965; 85055 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Radio and TV records, 1967-1975; 85054 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - WBAI programs, "Rent and Housing", 1969-1974; 85053 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Rockaway Low-income Housing Proposal, 1962; 85052 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Riverwalk, 1987; 85051 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Riverton, 1973; 85050 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Riverside South, 1992; 85049 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Resolution Trust Corporation, 1993; 85048 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Rent Strike Guide, undated; 85047 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Rockefeller University: Landlord, undated; 85046 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Roosevelt Hospital: Landlord, undated; 85045 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Save Our Cities March, 1992; 85044 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Northern Students Movement, 1965; 85043 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - National Housing Law Project, 1969; 85042 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Rooming Houses, undated; 85041 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - SROs, undated; 85040 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Lofts, undated; 85039 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Relocation, undated; 85038 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, undated; 85037 (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Housing Justice Campaign, undated; 85036 (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Ziman v. Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR), undated; 85035 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - Federal Housing, undated; 85034 (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - MCH: Senior Campaigns, 1977-1978; 85033 (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Rent Guidelines Board, 1999; 85032 (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - Tenant/Inquilino article on vacancy rate, Mar 1998; 85031 (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - MCH statements, 1960s-1970s; 85030 (Box 44, Folder 31)
  - Site Action Minutes, 1989; 85029 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Spring Beautification Project - Site Action, undated; 85028 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Mothers Against Drugs Site Action / War on Drugs, undated; 85027 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Site Action/Minutes, undated; 85026 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - East Third Street Playground, undated; 85025 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Site Action/Religious groups/War on Drugs, undated; 85024 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Site Action/Flyers, undated; 85023 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Blank letterhead paper, undated; 85022 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Cooper Square, undated; 85021 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 85020 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - 3 Kings Flyer Denis Oliver, 1988; 85019 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Block Captain Network, undated; 85018 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Site Action/War on Drugs, 1989; 85017 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Cooper Square Newsletter, undated; 85016 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Privat, undated; 85015 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - 7 Second Avenue, undated; 85014 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Joint Planning Committee, 1993-1995; 85013 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Strategy Committee, undated; 85012 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - 7 East Third Street, undated; 85011 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - 9 East Third Street, undated; 85010 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - 21 East Third Street, undated; 85009 (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - 23 East Third Street, undated; 85008 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - 23 East Third Street, undated; 85007 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - 25 East Third Street, undated; 85006 (Box 46, Folder S3)
  - 27 East Third Street, undated; 85005 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - 56 East Fourth Street, undated; 85004 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - 60 East Fourth Street, undated; 85003 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - 65 East Fourth Street, undated; 85002 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - 65 East Fourth Street, undated; 85001 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - 65 East Fourth Street, undated; 85000 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - 63 East Fourth Street, undated; 84999 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - 63 East Fourth Street, undated; 84998 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - 63 East Fourth Street, undated; 84997 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - 57 East Fourth Street, undated; 84996 (Box 46, Folder 13)
- Series IV: 2008 Accretion, 1951-2005; 84488; 8 Linear Feet
  This series contains subject and administrative files relating to the themes covered in Series I and II; topics and organizations most prominently represented include the Division of Housing and Community Renewal, rent control and rent stabilization, co-op conversions, and lobbying activity in Albany, New York.
  - Albany, 1989-1991; 84791 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Albany, 1995; 84790 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Albany Lobby Day, 1994; 84789 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Albany Legislation, 1995; 84788 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - City Council Legislation, 1994; 84787 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - City Owned Building, 1970-1977; 84786 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Cuomo Campaign, 1994; 84785 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Dinkins, 1986-1991; 84784 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Disabled Coalition NYC/Coalition for Housing for Disabled People, 1980-1987; 84783 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Energy, 1977-1983; 84782 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Evictions, 1975-1993; 84781 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Evictions, 1984-1986; 84780 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Fair Housing, 1961-1984; 84779 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Handicapped, 1974-1990; 84778 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - In REM, 1978-1982; 84777 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - In REM, 1978-1985; 84776 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - In REM HPD (city owned building), 1970-1985; 84775 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - In REM HPD (city owned building), 1980-1983; 84774 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - In REM Legislation, 1978-1982; 84773 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Legislative, 1994; 84772 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Park Conservation, 1964; 84771 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Pataki, 1994-2003; 84770 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Racism, 1986-1987; 84769 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Racism/Segregation, 1964-1973; 84768 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Rent Stabilization Code Revision, 1994; 84767 (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Starret City, 1984; 84766 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Tenants Unity Coalition, 1987-1988; 84765 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Tenants Unity Coalition, 1989-1992; 84764 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Views Harlem Parents Committee, 1965-1966; 84763 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Waterside Housing Development, 1967-1975; 84762 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Williamsburg, 1961-1963; 84761 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - 48th District Election, 1999; 84760 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Annadale Hugenont, 1963; 84759 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Berkeley Rent Control Decision, 1985; 84758 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Commercial rent Regulation, 1971-1985; 84757 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Cooper Square Project Dilemma, 1986-2002; 84756 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Federal Housing Policy Regulation #403, 1975-1977; 84755 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Federal Rent Guidelines, 1971-1972; 84754 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Fuel Cost Adjustment, 1991; 84753 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Fuel Costs (I), 1979-1989; 84752 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Fuel Costs (II), 1990; 84751 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Garrison Pataki Demonstration, 2002-2004; 84750 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Housing Politics and Theory, 1986-1991; 84749 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Housing Rehabilitation, 1981; 84748 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Housing Vacancy Survey, 1981-2001; 84747 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Lower East Side Joint Planning, 1987-1990; 84746 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - MBR, 1979; 84745 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - MBR, 1987; 84744 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - MBR (I), 1997; 84743 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - MBR (II), 1997; 84742 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - MBR, 1998; 84741 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - MBR, 2000-2001; 84740 (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - MBR, 2002; 84739 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - MBR Campaign, Nov 1995; 84738 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - MBR Fall, 1993; 84737 (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1961-2003; 84736 (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - News and Press Releases, 1979; 84735 (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - Political Action Committee, 1995-1998; 84734 (Box 48, Folder 32)
  - Property Tax, 1987-2003; 84733 (Box 48, Folder 33)
  - Public Housing, 1967-1997; 84732 (Box 48, Folder 34)
  - Redlining, 1974-1976; 84731 (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - Relocation, 1962-1980; 84730 (Box 48, Folder 36)
  - Rent Guidelines Board, 1985; 84729 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Rent Guidelines Board Rent Formulas, 1990-1991; 84728 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Rent Laws, 1999-2003; 84727 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Rent Laws (City), 1994; 84726 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Rent Regulations, 1994-1996; 84725 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - 575 Hancock St., undated; 84724 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Albany, 1990; 84723 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Albany, 1991; 84722 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Albany, 1992; 84721 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Albany, 1993; 84720 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Albany Tenant Unity Coalition, 1993; 84719 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Anti-unauthorized Occupant Campaign, 1992; 84718 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Appleby, Thomas, 1976; 84717 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Barbaro, Frank, 1981; 84716 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Bell Park Gardens, 1976; 84715 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Breezy Point, 1962-1968; 84714 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Brown, Rick, 1987; 84713 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Bumpers, Eleanor, 1984-1987; 84712 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council, 1972-1985; 84711 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Cohn, Roy, 1951-1969; 84710 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Columbia University Evictions, 1975-1989; 84709 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Community Resource Exchange, undated; 84708 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Cuomo, Andrew, 1987; 84707 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Damato, Al, 1981-1997; 84706 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Economics of Real Estate, 1977-1980; 84705 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Evans, Lester, 1976-1987; 84704 (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - Fair Housing/March For Jobs And Freedom, 1963-1967; 84703 (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Gray, Jesse, 1985-1988; 84702 (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Green, Mark, 2001; 84701 (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Homesteading, 1976; 84700 (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Housing and Development Administration Reorganization, 1975-1977; 84699 (Box 49, Folder 31)
  - Kamiat, Edith, 2005; 84698 (Box 49, Folder 32)
  - La Larouche, 1970-1997; 84697 (Box 49, Folder 33)
  - Landlords and Developers West Side, 1974; 84696 (Box 49, Folder 34)
  - Landlords Organization v. Rent Control Stabilization Laws, 1997; 84695 (Box 49, Folder 35)
  - Lehman, Franz, 2000; 84694 (Box 49, Folder 36)
  - Lincoln Center Tower Square, 1977-1994; 84693 (Box 49, Folder 37)
  - Logue, Edward, 1966; 84692 (Box 49, Folder 38)
  - Lopez, Margacita, 1997-1998; 84691 (Box 49, Folder 39)
  - Messinger, Ruth, undated; 84690 (Box 49, Folder 40)
  - New Alliance Party (I), 1982; 84689 (Box 49, Folder 41)
  - New Alliance Party (II), 1982; 84688 (Box 49, Folder 42)
  - Political Action Committee, 1994-2003; 84687 (Box 49, Folder 43)
  - Queens, Flushing, 1965; 84686 (Box 49, Folder 44)
  - Queens, General, 1967-1991; 84685 (Box 49, Folder 45)
  - Queens, Jamaica, 1962-1963; 84684 (Box 49, Folder 46)
  - Rehabilitation, 1974-1977; 84683 (Box 49, Folder 47)
  - Rent Regulation Reform, 1994; 84682 (Box 49, Folder 48)